<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[untitled blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[A junior developer's musings, explorations, and learnings of all things technology.]]></description><link>https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:22:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Tech Intersections 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[Last weekend, I had the immense pleasure to attend  Tech Intersections 
hosted at my alma mater,  Mills College .  As described on the…]]></description><link>https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//Tech-Intersections/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//Tech-Intersections/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I had the immense pleasure to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://techintersections.org&quot;&gt;Tech Intersections&lt;/a&gt;
hosted at my alma mater, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mills.edu&quot;&gt;Mills College&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described on the website: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Intersections is an affordable conference for the womxn of color most underrepresented in tech
to come together and learn from each other’s successes, challenges, and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was this conference a chance to visit Mills — my second home — but it afforded me the opportunity
to engage in a community within tech that I often feel starved of in Minnesota. This is not to say that my
current place of work isn’t inclusive or supportive, but that it’s vastly white and male. On my current team,
I believe I was the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; woman to join. And I joined a mere six months after the first woman joined. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[I made a favicon using Sketch]]></title><description><![CDATA[When it comes to being creative, I’ve  always  had high hopes and aspirations. But like the ♓️I am, I let myself get lazy and end up with…]]></description><link>https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//i-made-a-favicon/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//i-made-a-favicon/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;When it comes to being creative, I’ve &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; had high hopes and aspirations.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like the ♓️I am, I let myself get lazy and end up with lots of unfinished
projects: &lt;em&gt;I’m looking directly at an unfinished canvas as I type this.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.tenor.com/images/b8cfc069b7f6b3c7b6479935d5bfa744/tenor.gif?itemid=4519756&quot; alt=&quot;lazy seal gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the off chance that I have a spurt of inspiration and drive to complete
something for myself, I tend to become obsessive over the tiniest of details
and &lt;strong&gt;spend hours&lt;/strong&gt; trying to get something &lt;em&gt;just right&lt;/em&gt;. Whoever said &lt;em&gt;you are your own worst enemy&lt;/em&gt;
couldn’t have of been more right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the creation of this blog, for example, I spent a couple &lt;strong&gt;hours&lt;/strong&gt; alone trying to decide on a color palette —
looking for colors I liked that were also widely accessible. To accomplish this, I used a combination of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://colorsafe.co/&quot;&gt;Color Safe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mycolor.space/&quot;&gt;Color Space&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://paletton.com/&quot;&gt;Paletton&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/resources/contrastchecker/&quot;&gt;Web Aim Color Contrast Checker&lt;/a&gt;. After spending a couple
hours on a color palette alone, I was quickly burnt out on all work for this blog so I published and called it
quits for the night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, I checked the blog to realize I hadn’t changed the favicon (something I was most excited about creating)
to something of my own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pm1.narvii.com/6294/52f5bc75583630946a5b06ef1df63b34f68e2950_128.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homer Simpson &amp;#x22;doh&amp;#x22;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to kill 2 birds with 1 stone, I decided that I would practice time-boxing myself and my advance Sketch skills
by creating a favicon for myself. I knew that I wanted the icon to be a 🍍 — pineapples have been a symbolic part
of my life for some years now — but I was unsure of how I wanted the icon to look and feel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting down to business to create a favicon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time-box&lt;/strong&gt;: drawing a pineapple icon I liked.
To accomplish this task, I gave myself 10 minutes to roughly sketch something out. Within the time constraints, I was
able to create a pencil version of a pineapple I actually liked quite a bit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I somewhat cheated after my allotted time, and used up another 5min to color the drawing in so I would have more
reference when transforming the drawing into an icon. This is the finalized drawing: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KtClT8X.png&quot; alt=&quot;my first pineapple drawing&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a drawing I was happy with, I was ready to open up Sketch and getting to vectorizing! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second time-box&lt;/strong&gt;: excercising my Sketch skills.
To create my icon, I chose Sketch because it’s a standard tool that UX designers at Target use and because
I know it to be new user-friendly. In college, though I created a handful of websites from the ground up, the
teams I was on were never concerned with — or given an opportunity to —fully explore design and user experience,
so I never had much opportunity to learn design toolings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/sketch-app-sources/how-to-use-sketch-to-build-great-icons-9c3d982ae91d&quot;&gt;Sketch icon tutorial by Christian Krammeron&lt;/a&gt;
to get a better idea of the tools I could use and where to even start. Knowing that I would be learning Sketch
as I attempted to vectorize my drawing, I gave myself a time-box of 1 hour and still fumbled around a lot of that hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This the icon I created at the end of that hour: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/njeS3bft.png?1&quot; alt=&quot;my first draft of the pineapple icon made using Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that exercise I experienced a lot of pain points in how I was using Sketch: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🎨 For the crown, I used the vector tool to draw individual points that I connected with rounded edges rather than
using a shape tool to get uniformity off the bat&lt;br&gt;
🎨 I created all the lines on the body and then one-by-one curved them&lt;br&gt;
🎨 The fill tool wasn’t giving me the right blend and overall feel I was hoping for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third time’s a charm?&lt;/strong&gt;
I was not very pleased with my first pineapple iteration, and particularly not happy with how Sketch plays with color blends.
I pivoted my pineapple design to be more minimalist and cohesive with the color palette I chose for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of using the vector tool to draw out the crown, I chose to use the star tool to create the size I wanted and then
rounded out the stars edges and curved the connecting lines. For the minimalist look, I stripped out all fill colors and
changed the color of the pineapple line to be #1ca086 &lt;img src=&quot;https://placehold.it/15/1ca086/000000?text=+&quot; alt=&quot;#1ca086&quot;&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current icon: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xsSkIMkt.png&quot; alt=&quot;minimalized pineapple icon&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s in no way perfect, but I’m happy with where the icon ended up and much more comfortable with using Sketch to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan on further iterating on the icon, but now feel much more confident in my ability to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ time-box myself&lt;br&gt;
✅ use Sketch and learn how to best optimize my skills&lt;br&gt;
✅ express my own creativity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.tenor.com/images/f69b9aa3e004ddbb4664934b12c8d6a6/tenor.gif?itemid=5207407&quot; alt=&quot;success kid&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Obligatory "Hello World" post]]></title><description><![CDATA[Look! I  actually  made progress on a side project! I started this blog — entitled “untitled blog” until I 
can think of a name I like — not…]]></description><link>https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https:/susanafotu.github.io/untitled-bloggs//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;Look! I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; made progress on a side project!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/images/424b004561d02b05588d5ce8e3ab4136/tenor.gif&quot; alt=&quot;excited dance gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this blog — entitled “untitled blog” until I
can think of a name I like — not only as a way to
communicate and hold myself accountable for what
I am learning, mulling over, and experiencing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What I hope to accomplish here&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☀️ Document my own learning, thoughts, and experiences&lt;br&gt;
☀️ Learn more about GatsbyJS &amp;#x26; specifically GraphQL&lt;br&gt;
☀️ Achieve one of my 2019 goals  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How I hope to accomplish the above&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☁️ Write and publish pieces once every week&lt;br&gt;
☁️ Alternate the topic / method of each written pieces&lt;br&gt;
☁️ Maintain self-accountability &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major ups to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org&quot;&gt;GatsbyJS&lt;/a&gt; and
their amazing docs that allowed me to get up and running
almost immediately. A post in the very near future will
be about my experience working with Gatsby and my
thoughts, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further adieu, I leave you with an adorable
pupper gif while I continue working on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://thumbs.gfycat.com/FatScholarlyCondor-max-1mb.gif&quot; alt=&quot;a puppy falling on the ground after being distracted by a leaf and a ball&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>